Register of the Pathfinder Press Publications, 1922-2014
Hoover Institution Archives
- PATHFINDER PRESS IMPRINTS, 1969-1993. (Box 6-23)
  - Reed, Evelyn. Woman's Evolution: From Matriarchal Clan to Patriarchal Family. 491 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Iran, Mexico, Spain, Sweden, Turkey) imprints, 1974. (Box 15)
  - Reid, Willie Mae. The Racist Offensive against Busing: The Lessons of Boston. By Willie Mae Reid, Peter Camejo and others. 30 p., 1974.
  - Smith, Baxter. FBI Plot against the Black Movement: Secret Documents Exposed. 23 p., 1974.
  - Thomas, Tony. Marxism versus Maoism: A Reply to The Guardian. 31 p., 1974.
  - Thomas, Tony. What Road to Black Liberation: The Democratic Party or an Independent Black Party? By Tony Thomas and Norman Oliver. 21 p., 1974.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Against Individual Terrorism. 23 p., 1974.
  - ----------. 3rd printing. 23 p., 1987.
  - Weinstein, Nat. Construction Workers under Attack: How to Fight Back and Rebuild the Unions. By Nat Weinstein, Frank Lovell and Carol Lipman. 23 p., 1974.
  - Which Way for Teachers? By Maceo Dixon et al. 22 p., 1974.
  - Yellen, Samuel. American Labor Struggles, 1877-1934. 398 p., 1974.
  - Camejo, Peter. Who Killed Jim Crow? The Story of the Civil Rights Movement and Its Lessons for Today. 29 p., 1975.
  - Cannon, James P. America's Road to Socialism. 2nd edition. 124 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers (1953, q.v.), 1975.
  - Cannon, James P. The Revolutionary Party: Its Role in the Struggle for Socialism. 15 p., 1975.
  - ----------. 2nd printing. 15 p., 1979.
  - ----------. 3rd printing. 15 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Canada) imprint, 1985.
  - Cannon, James P. The Socialist Workers Party in World War II: Writings and Speeches, 1940-43. 446 p., 1975.
  - Curtin, Katie. Women in China. 95 p., 1975.
  - Dawson, Kipp. Gay Liberation: A Socialist Perspective. 13 p., 1975.
  - La Dialectica actual de la revolucion mundial [Dynamics of World Revolution Today. Spanish translation] 189 p. Cf. 1974 imprint, 1975.
  - Last Hired, First Fired: Affirmative Action vs. Seniority. By Linda Jenness et al. 30 p., 1975.
  - Lenin, V. I. Lenin's Fight against Stalinism. By V. I. Lenin and Leon Trotsky; edited by Russell Block. 160 p., 1975.
  - Life in Capitalist America: Private Profit and Social Decay. By Stephanie Coontz et al. 285 p., 1975.
  - Lobman, Ethel. The Struggle for Community Control in N.Y. School District 1. By Ethel Lobman and Katherine Sojourner. 15 p., 1975.
  - Lovell, Frank. The Job Crisis: A New Challenge for the Unions. 14 p., 1975.
  - Lund, Caroline. Detente: Why It Won't Bring Peace. By Caroline Lund and Dick Roberts. 31 p., 1975.
  - Novack, George. Pragmatism versus Marxism: An Appraisal of John Dewey's Philosophy. 320 p., 1975.
  - Roberts, Dick. Capitalism in Crisis. 128 p., 1975.
  - Thomas, Tony. A Strategy for Black Liberation. 29 p., 1975.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Challenge of the Left Opposition, 1923-29. 3 volumes, 1975-1981. (Box 15-16)
  - Abortion Rights in Danger! By Nancy Brown et al. 23 p., 1976. (Box 16)
  - America's Revolutionary Heritage: Marxist Essays. Edited by George Novack. Revised edition of Marxist Essays in American History. 414 p. First published by Merit Publishers (1966, q.v.), 1976.
  - Breitman, George. The Assassination of Malcolm X. By George Breitman, Herman Porter and Baxter Smith; edited by Malik Miah. 190 p., 1976.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 190 p. Cf. 1969 imprint, 1988.
  - Dictatorship in India. By Ernest Harsch et al. 31 p., 1976.
  - Heisler, Ed. A Struggle for Union Democracy: The Story of the Right to Vote Committee in the United Transportation Union. 46 p., 1976.
  - James P. Cannon as We Knew Him. By thirty-three comrades, friends, and relatives. 288 p., 1976.
  - Jenness, Linda. Socialism and the Fight for Women's Rights. 15 p., 1976.
  - Miah, Malik. Busing and the Black Struggle. 29 p., 1976.
  - Pendas, Miguel. Chicano Liberation and Socialism. 15 p., 1976.
  - Perez, Jose G. Puerto Rico: U.S. Colony in the Caribbean. 23 p., 1976.
  - Prospects for Socialism in America. By Jack Barnes et al.; edited by Jack Barnes and Mary-Alice Waters. 267 p., 1976.
  - Reid, Willie Mae. Black Women's Struggle for Equality. 15 p., 1976.
  - Rose, Andy. The Fight for Union Democracy in Steel. 38 p., 1976.
  - Thomas, Tony. The Freedom Struggle in South Africa. 23 p., 1976.
  - Waters, Mary-Alice. Women and the Socialist Revolution. 30 p., 1976.
  - ----------. 3rd printing. 30 p., 1989.
  - Young Socialist Alliance. Education Is Our Right! A Socialist Answer to the Crisis Facing Youth. 38 p., 1976.
  - Camejo, Peter. Stop the Deportations! / Que cesen las deportaciones! 1977. p. Texts in English and Spanish, 14, 15
  - Cannon, James P. The Struggle for Socialism in the "American Century": Writings and Speeches, 1945-47. 480 p., 1977.
  - Foner, Philip S. The Great Labor Uprising of 1877. 288 p., 1977.
  - Gay Liberation Today: An Exchange of Views. By Cheryl Adams et al. 39 p., 1977.
  - Hillson, Jon. The Battle of Boston. 286 p., 1977.
  - How to Win the ERA. By Ginny Hildebrand et al. 31 p., 1977.
  - Jaquith, Cindy. Which Way for the Women's Movement? By Cindy Jaquith and Willie Mae Reid. 31 p., 1977.
  - Kerry, Tom. The Mao Myth: And the Legacy of Stalinism in China. 190 p., 1977.
  - The Lesser Evil? The Left Debates the Democratic Party and Social Change. By Michael Harrington et al. 128 p., 1977.
  - The Politics of Chicano Liberation. Edited by Olga Rodriguez. 159 p., 1977.
  - Puerto Ricans in the U.S.: The Struggle for Freedom. Edited by Catarino Garza. 63 p., 1977. (Box 17)
  - Ring, Harry. Socialism and Individual Freedom. 22 p., 1977.
  - ----------. 2nd printing. 22 p., 1982.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Crisis of the French Section, 1935-36. 286 p., 1977.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Portraits: Political and Personal. 237 p., 1977.
  - Wang, Diane. FBI vs. Women. By Diane Wang and Cindy Jaquith. 47 p., 1977.
  - Blanco, Hugo. Workers and Peasants to Power! A Revolutionary Program for Peru. 46 p., 1978.
  - Breton, Andre. What is Surrealism? Selected Writings. Edited by Franklin Rosemont. 389 p., 1978.
  - Cole, Nancy. The 110-Day Coal Strike: Its Meaning for All Working People. By Nancy Cole and Andy Rose. 39 p., 1978.
  - Frankel, Dave. Upsurge in Africa: Cuba, the U.S., and the New Rise of the African Liberation Struggle. 31 p., 1978.
  - Hansen, Joseph. Dynamics of the Cuban Revolution: The Trotskyist View. 393 p., 1978.
  - Harsch, Ernest. The Ethiopian Revolution. 38 p., 1978.
  - Reed, Evelyn. Sexism and Science. 190 p., 1978.
  - ----------. 3rd printing. 190 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Greece) imprint, 1989.
  - Blackstock, Nelson. Workers in the Changing South: The Impact of the Civil Rights Movement. 30 p., 1979.
  - Breitman, George. Malcolm X: The Man and His Ideas. 13th printing. 22 p. First published by Merit Publishers. Cf. Related Foreign (Italy) imprint, 1979.
  - Castro, Fidel. We Represent the Immense Majority of Humanity. 46 p., 1979.
  - Halstead, Fred. What Working People Should Know about the Dangers of Nuclear Power. 39 p., 1979.
  - Hansen, Joseph. The Leninist Strategy of Party Building: The Debate on Guerrilla Warfare in Latin America. 608 p., 1979.
  - The Nicaraguan Revolution. Edited by Pedro Camejo and Fred Murphy. 79 p., 1979.
  - Novack, George. The Long View of History. 3rd edition. 46 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers (1960, q.v.), 1979.
  - Rose, Andy. The Weber Case: New Threat to Affirmative Action. 31 p., 1979.
  - Women's Liberation and the Socialist Revolution. 93 p., 1979.
  - El Salvador: Un pueblo en lucha. 46 p., 1980.
  - James, C. L. R. Fighting Racism in World War II. By C. L. R. James, George Breitman, Edgar Keemer and others. 376 p., 1980.
  - Kerry, Tom. Workers, Bosses, and Bureaucrats: A Socialist View of Labor Struggles since the 1930s. 285 p., 1980. (Box 18)
  - Novack, George. Understanding History: Marxist Essays. 3rd edition. 208 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Colombia, Mexico) imprints, 1980.
  - Revolt in El Salvador. p., 1980? 47
  - Roberts, Dick. American Railroads: The Case for Nationalization. 109 p., 1980.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The History of the Russian Revolution. 3 volumes in 1. Cf. Monad (1976) imprint, 1980.
  - Cannon, James P. Wall Street enjuicia al socialismo [Socialism on Trial. Spanish translation] 2nd edition. 188 p. Cf. 1973, Pioneer (1942) and Merit (1969) imprints, 1981.
  - Castro, Fidel. Speeches: Cuba's Internationalist Foreign Policy, 1975-80. 391 p., 1981.
  - Castro, Fidel. Women and the Cuban Revolution: Speeches and Documents. By Fidel Castro, Vilma Espin and others; edited by Elizabeth Stone. 156 p. Cf. 1970 imprint, 1981.
  - Coal Miners on Strike. 55 p., 1981.
  - Conner, Cliff. Evolution vs. Creationism: In Defense of Scientific Thinking. 46 p., 1981.
  - ----------. 2nd printing. 46 p., 1988.
  - Frankel, Dave. Poland: Workers in Revolt. By Dave Frankel, DeAnn Rathbun and Ernest Harsch. 46 p., 1981.
  - Harsch, Ernest. U.S. Intervention in Jamaica: How Washington Toppled the Manley Government. 29 p., 1981.
  - Jacobs, W. Richard. The Grenada Revolution at Work. 15 p., 1981.
  - Jayko, Margaret. Reagan's War on Women's Rights: A Strategy to Fight Back. 38 p., 1981.
  - Lynn, Janice. Imperialism vs. the Iranian Revolution: Which Side for Working People? By Janice Lynn and David Frankel. 39 p., 1981.
  - Manuel, Sam. Grenada: Revolution in the Caribbean. By Sam Manuel and Andrew Pulley. 35 p., 1981.
  - Murphy, Fred. El Salvador: Why the U.S. Government Hides the Truth. 31 p., 1981.
  - Seigle, Larry. Workers' Rights versus the Secret Police. 46 p., 1981.
  - Socialist Workers Party. The Changing Face of U.S. Politics: Building a Party of Socialist Workers: Reports and Resolutions. Edited by Jack Barnes and Steve Clark. 346 p., 1981.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The War Correspondence of Leon Trotsky: The Balkan Wars, 1912-13. 524 p., 1981.
  - Weissberg, Arnold. Nicaragua: An Introduction to the Sandinista Revolution. 47 p., 1981.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 45 p., 1987.
  - Yanez, Anibal. The Struggle for Freedom in Guatemala. 31 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Mexico) imprint, 1981.
  - Borge, Tomas. Women and the Nicaraguan Revolution. 30 p. Cf. 1983 imprint, 1982. (Box 19)
  - Castro, Fidel. The U.S. War Drive and the World Economic Crisis. 31 p. Cf. 1983 imprint, 1982.
  - Mason, Mel. The Making of a Revolutionary. 40 p., 1982.
  - Sandinistas Speak. By Tomas Borge et al. 160 p., 1982.
  - Studer, John. Attack on Workers' Rights: The Fight against Government/Company Victimizations. 23 p., 1982.
  - Bishop, Maurice. Maurice Bishop Speaks: The Grenada Revolution and Its Overthrow, 1979-83. 352 p., 1983.
  - Bishop, Maurice. Maurice Bishop Speaks to U.S. Workers: Why the U.S. Invaded Grenada. 48 p., 1983.
  - Borge, Tomas. La mujer y la revolucion nicaraguense [Women and the Nicaraguan Revolution. Spanish version] 31 p. Cf. 1982 imprint, 1983.
  - Castro, Fidel. El guerrerismo de EUA y la crisis economica mundial [The U.S. War Drive and the World Economic Crisis. Spanish version] 32 p. Cf. 1982 imprint, 1983.
  - Castro, Fidel. Our Power Is That of the Working People: Building Socialism in Cuba. 367 p., 1983.
  - Frankel, Dave. Israel's War against the Palestinian People. By David Frankel and Will Reissner. 45 p., 1983.
  - Hillson, Jon. A Socialist View of the Chicago Election: Forging a Black-Latino-Labor Alliance. By Jon Hillson, Malik Miah and Mac Warren. 31 p., 1983.
  - McAliskey, Bernadette Devlin. Bernadette Devlin McAliskey on the Irish Freedom Struggle. 16 p., 1983.
  - Mirelowitz, Geoff. Steelworkers under Attack: How to Fight Back and Defend Jobs. 39 p., 1983.
  - Bishop, Maurice. La revolucion granadina, 1979-83: Discursos. By Maurice Bishop and Fidel Castro. 86 p., 1984.
  - Castro, Fidel. The Second Declaration of Havana. Bound with Fidel Castro, The First Declaration of Havana. 4th printing. 31 p. First published by Pioneer Publishers (1962, q.v.), 1984.
  - Wang, Diane. Report from Vietnam and Kampuchea. By Diane Wang and Steve Clark. 70 p. Cf. 1987 imprint, 1984.
  - X, Malcolm. Habla Malcolm X: La lucha por la liberacion negra en EUA. 62 p. Cf. 1989 and Merit (1965) imprints, 1984.
  - Castro, Fidel. War and Crisis in the Americas: Speeches, 1984-85. 249 p., 1985.
  - Grogan, Pat. Abortion Is a Woman's Right! By Pat Grogan, Jose G. Perez and Evelyn Reed. 44 p., 1985.
  - Grogan, Pat. El aborto: Derecho fundamental de la mujer [Abortion Is a Woman's Right! Spanish translation] By Pat Grogan, Jose G. Perez and Evelyn Reed. 46 p., 1985.
  - Nicaragua: The Sandinista People's Revolution: Speeches. By Sandinista leaders. 412 p., 1985.
  - Barnes, Jack. Sudafrica: La revolucion en camino. 75 p., 1986.
  - Castro, Fidel. Fidel and Religion: Conversations with Frei Betto. Sydney: Pathfinder Press/Pacific and Asia, 268 p., 1986.
  - Castro, Fidel. Nothing Can Stop the Course of History. 258 p., 1986.
  - Deutscher, Isaac. On Socialist Man. 4th printing. 29 p. First published by Merit Publishers (1967, q.v.), 1986.
  - The German Revolution and the Debate on Soviet Power: Documents, 1918-1919, Preparing the Founding Congress [of the Communist International] Edited by John Riddell. 540 p., 1986.
  - Guevara, Ernesto. Socialism and Man. 8th printing. 1986. 22 p. First published by Merit Publishers. Cf. imprints, 1988 and 1992 (Box 20)
  - Halstead, Fred. The 1985-86 Hormel Meat-Packers Strike in Austin, Minnesota. 44 p., 1986.
  - Halstead, Fred. La huelga de los obreros de la carne contra la Hormel en Austin Minnesota, 1985-86 [The 1985-86 Hormel Meat-Packers Strike in Austin, Minnesota. Spanish translation] 53 p., 1986.
  - Hansen, Joseph. Cosmetics, Fashions, and the Exploitation of Women. By Joseph Hansen and Evelyn Reed. 138 p., 1986.
  - Harsch, Ernest. Apartheid's Great Land Theft: The Struggle for the Right to Farm in South Africa. 50 p., 1986.
  - Mandela, Nelson. Habla Nelson Mandela. 84 p. Cf. 1993 and Related Foreign (Cuba) imprints, 1986.
  - Mandela, Nelson. The Struggle Is My Life. 249 p., 1986.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 281 p., 1990.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Permanent Revolution. Bound with Leon Trotsky, Results and Prospects. 7th printing. 281 p. Reprint of Merit Publishers edition (1969, q.v.) Cf. Pioneer (1931) and Related Foreign (Spain) imprints, 1986.
  - Castro, Fidel. Cancelar la deuda de America Latina! 43 p., 1987.
  - Communist International. Congress (1st: 1919: Moscow, Russia) Founding the Communist International: Proceedings and Documents of the First Congress, March 1919. Edited by John Riddell. 424 p., 1987.
  - Guevara, Ernesto. Che Guevara and the Cuban Revolution: Writings and Speeches of Ernesto Che Guevara. Edited by David Deutschmann. Sydney: Pathfinder/Pacific and Asia, 413 p., 1987.
  - ----------. Philippine reprint. 413 p.
  - Guevara, Ernesto. Che Guevara Speaks: Selected Speeches and Writings. 5th printing. 159 p. First published by Merit Publishers. Cf. Related Foreign (Japan) imprint, 1987.
  - Hansen, Beatrice. A Political Biography of Walter Reuther: The Record of an Opportunist. 2nd edition. 27 p. First published by Merit Publishers (1969, q.v.), 1987.
  - Harnecker, Marta. Fidel Castro's Political Strategy: From Moncada to Victory. 157 p., 1987.
  - Wang, Diane. Reportaje de Vietnam y Kampuchea [Report from Vietnam and Kampuchea. Spanish translation] By Diane Wang and Steve Clark. 77 p. Cf. 1984 imprint, 1987.
  - X, Malcolm. Two Speeches. 2nd edition. 47 p. First published by Merit Publishers, 1987.
  - ----------. 3rd edition. 47 p., 1990.
  - Blackstock, Nelson. COINTELPRO: The FBI's Secret War on Political Freedom. 3rd edition. 190 p., 1988.
  - Castro, Fidel. Cuba Will Never Adopt Capitalist Methods. 30 p., 1988.
  - ----------. 2nd printing. 30 p., 1990.
  - Castro, Fidel. Verdum eins og Che [Speech on the Twentieth Anniversary of the Death of Che Guevara. Icelandic translation] 30 p., 1988.
  - FBI on Trial: The Victory in the Socialist Workers Party Suit against Government Spying. Edited by Margaret Jayko. 260 p., 1988.
  - Guevara, Ernesto. Socialism and Man in Cuba. Sydney: Pathfinder/Pacific and Asia, 37 p., 1988. (Box 21)
  - ----------. U.S. reprint. 1989. 44 p. Cf. imprints, 1986, 1989 and 1992
  - Guevara, Ernesto. El socialismo y el hombre en Cuba [Socialism and Man in Cuba. Spanish version] Sydney: Pathfinder/Pacific and Asia, 39 p., 1988.
  - Jaquith, Cindy. Surrogate Motherhood, Women's Rights, and the Working Class. 23 p., 1988.
  - Marroquin, Hector. Cincuenta anos de guerra encubierta: El FBI contra los derechos democraticos. By Hector Marroquin, Margaret Jayko and Larry Seigle. 70 p., 1988.
  - One People, One Destiny: The Caribbean and Central America Today. Edited by Don Rojas. 115 p., 1988.
  - Sankara, Thomas. Thomas Sankara Speaks: The Burkina Faso Revolution, 1983-87. 260 p. Cf. 1991 imprint, 1988.
  - Socialist Workers Party. National Committee. Action Program to Confront the Coming Economic Crisis. 32 p., 1988.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 1989. 34 p. Cf. imprints, 1989 and 1990
  - Socialist Workers Party. National Committee. Un programa de accion para enfrentar la crisis economica que se avecina [Action Program to Confront the Coming Economic Crisis. Spanish translation] 35 p., 1988.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 42 p., 1989.
  - Castro, Fidel. In Defense of Socialism: Four Speeches on the Thirtieth Anniversary of the Cuban Revolution. Edited by Mary-Alice Waters. 142 p., 1989.
  - Feldman, Fred. Palestine and the Arabs' Fight for Liberation. By Fred Feldman and Georges Sayad. 62 p., 1989.
  - Guevara, Ernesto. Insan va susyalism dar Kuba [Socialism and Man in Cuba. Persian translation] 76 p. Cf. 1988 imprint, 1989.
  - Guevara, Ernesto. Le socialisme et l'homme a Cuba [Socialism and Man in Cuba. French translation] 53 p. Cf. 1988 imprint, 1989.
  - Guevara, Ernesto. Socialismen och mannisk an pa Kuba [Socialism and Man in Cuba. Swedish translation] 42 p. Cf. 1988 imprint, 1989.
  - Jayko, Margaret. The Frame-up of Mark Curtis: A Packinghouse Worker's Fight for Justice. 71 p., 1989.
  - Socialist Workers Party. National Committee. Adgerda stefnuskra vegna komandi efnahagskreppu [Action Program to Confront the Coming Economic Crisis. Icelandic translation] Reykjavik, 35 p. Cf. 1988 imprint, 1989.
  - Tablada, Carlos. Che Guevara: Economics and Politics in the Transition to Socialism. Sydney: Pathfinder/Pacific and Asia, 286 p., 1989.
  - ----------. 2nd (U.S.) edition. 286 p. Cf. 1992 imprint, 1990.
  - X, Malcolm. The Last Speeches. Edited by Bruce Perry. 189 p., 1989.
  - ----------. 4th printing. 189 p. Cf. Related Foreign (France) imprint, 1992.
  - X, Malcolm. Malcolm X Speaks. 2nd cloth edition. 1989. 233 p. First published by Merit Publishers (1965, q.v.) Cf. Related U.S. (1966) and Related Foreign (France, Italy, Japan, Sweden) imprints, 1984, 1993
  - Breitman, George. The Last Year of Malcolm X: The Evolution of a Revolutionary. 10th printing. 169 p. First published by Merit Publishers, 1990.
  - Castro, Fidel. U.S. Hands Off the Mideast! Cuba Speaks Out at the United Nations. By Fidel Castro and Ricardo Alarcon. 81 p., 1990.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 126 p., 1990.
  - Castro, Fidel. EE.UU. fuera del Oriente Medio! Cuba habla en Naciones Unidas [U.S. Hands Off the Mideast! Spanish version] By Fidel Castro and Ricardo Alarcon. 135 p., 1990.
  - Mandela, Nelson. Intensify the Struggle to Abolish Apartheid: Speeches, 1990. 74 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Argentina, Venezuela) imprints (Box 22)
  - Mandela, Nelson. Intensifiquemos la lucha: Discursos en Africa, Europa y Norteamerica [Intensify the Struggle to Abolish Apartheid. Spanish translation] 108 p., 1990.
  - Panama: The Truth about the U.S. Invasion. By Cindy Jaquith et al. 44 p., 1990.
  - Sankara, Thomas. Women's Liberation and the African Freedom Struggle. 36 p., 1990.
  - Socialist Workers Party. National Committee. Handlingsprogram for att bemota den kommande ekonomiska krisen [Action Program to Confront the Coming Economic Crisis. Swedish translation] Stockholm, 47 p. Cf. 1988 imprint, 1990.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Trade Unions in the Epoch of Imperialist Decay. Bound with Karl Marx, Trade Unions: Their Past, Present, and Future. 156 p., 1990.
  - Barnes, Jack. En arbetarklasskampanj mot imperialistiska krigsforberedelser. Stockholm, 102 p., 1991.
  - Communist International. Congress (2nd: 1920: Petrograd, Russia) Workers of the World and Oppressed Peoples, Unite! Proceedings and Documents of the Second Congress, 1920. Edited by John Riddell. 2 volumes, 1991.
  - Halstead, Fred. Out Now! A Participant's Account of the Movement in the U.S. against the Vietnam War. 2nd edition. 759 p. First published by Monad Press (1978, q.v.), 1991.
  - Mailhot, Ernie. The Eastern Airlines Strike: Accomplishments of the Rank-and-File Machinists and Gains for the Labor Movement. By Ernie Mailhot, Judy Stranahan and Jack Barnes. 91 p., 1991.
  - Mandela, Nelson. How Far We Slaves Have Come! South Africa and Cuba in Today's World. By Nelson Mandela and Fidel Castro. 83 p., 1991.
  - Mandela, Nelson. Que lejos hemos llegado los esclavos! Sudafrica y Cuba en el mundo de hoy [How Far We Slaves Have Come! Spanish translation] By Nelson Mandela and Fidel Castro. 83 p., 1991.
  - Sankara, Thomas. Oser inventer l'avenir: La parole de Sankara, 1983-1987 [Thomas Sankara Speaks. French version] Edited by David Gakunzi. Paris: Pathfinder and L'Harmattan, 290 p. Cf. 1988 imprint, 1991.
  - X, Malcolm. Malcolm X Talks to Young People: Speeches in the U.S., Britain, and Africa. 110 p. Cf. 1969 imprint, 1991.
  - Castro, Fidel. To Speak the Truth: Why Washington's "Cold War" against Cuba Doesn't End. By Fidel Castro and Ernesto Che Guevara. 232 p., 1992. (Box 23)
  - Guevara, Ernesto. El socialismo y el hombre en Cuba [Socialism and Man in Cuba. Spanish version] 1992. 145 p. Cf. imprints, 1986 and 1988
  - Jenness, Doug. Farmers Face the Crisis of the 1990s. 35 p., 1992.
  - Marx, Karl. El manifiesto comunista [The Communist Manifesto. Spanish translation] By Carlos Marx and Federico Engels. 63 p. Cf. 1970 imprint, 1992.
  - Pathfinder Press. Pathfinder Catalog 1992. 40 p.
  - Tablada, Carlos. Che Guevara: L'economie et la politique dans la transition au socialisme [Che Guevara: Economics and Politics in the Transition to Socialism. French translation] 310 p. Cf. 1989 imprint, 1992.
  - Trotsky, Leon. La revolucion traicionada: Que es y a donde se dirige la Union Sovietica? [The Revolution Betrayed. Spanish translation] 255 p. Cf. 1972 and Pioneer (1945) imprints, 1992.
  - Waters, Mary-Alice. Che Guevara and the Fight for Socialism Today: Cuba Confronts the World Crisis of the '90s. 37 p. Cf. 1993 imprint, 1992.
  - Waters, Mary-Alice. Che Guevara et la lutte pour le socialisme aujourd'hui: Cuba fait face a la crise mondiale des annees 90 [Che Guevara and the Fight for Socialism Today. French translation] 38 p., 1992.
  - Waters, Mary-Alice. Che Guevara y la lucha por el socialismo hoy: Cuba face frente a la crisis mundial de los anos 90 [Che Guevara and the Fight for Socialism Today. Spanish translation] 38 p., 1992.
  - X, Malcolm. February 1965: The Final Speeches. 293 p., 1992.
  - Congress of the Peoples of the East (1920: Baku, Azerbaijan) To See the Dawn: Baku, 1920: First Congress of the Peoples of the East. Edited by John Riddell. 344 p., 1993.
  - Mandela, Nelson. Nelson Mandela Speaks: Forging a Democratic, Nonracial South Africa. 296 p. Cf. 1986 imprint, 1993.
  - Waters, Mary-Alice. Che Guevara og barattan fyrir sosialisma i dag: Kuba andspaenis heimskreppu tiunda aratugarins [Che Guevara and the Fight for Socialism Today. Icelandic translation] 30 p. Cf. 1992 imprint, 1993.
  - X, Malcolm. Habla Malcolm X: Discursos, entrevistas y declaraciones [Malcolm X Speaks. Spanish translation] 233 p. Cf. 1989 and Merit (1965) imprints, 1993.
- MONAD PRESS IMPRINTS, 1972-1986. (Box 23-26)